# Damian Spears

## Contact

**Address** 

Chattanooga, TN 37404

**Phone** 

(615)-815-0404

E-mail

Ryanspears97@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/damian-spears/

www

https://github.com/DamianSpears

## **Skills**

Financial budgeting and reporting

Tenant and eviction laws

**Building operations** 

Advanced problem solving

Project planning and development

Agile

HTML and CSS proficiency

Java programming skills

Git

Github

Terminal Navigation

Dynamic and focused professional with 3 years of construction management experience spanning all phases of residential and commercial development. Experienced in organizing business operations, project oversight, and resource management to maintain efficient project operations. Looking to make a career switch into software engineering. Self-taught HTML and CSS, currently working on JavaScript and then learning jQuery, Node.js, SQL, MongoDB, React, Redux, Angular, and Python. Recently collaborated on a freelance project with a colleague in the tech industry and will continue to upload projects on Github.

## **Work History**

### 2022-03 -Current

#### Owner

Peak Cleaning, Chattanooga, TN

- Trained and motivated employees to perform daily business functions.
- Enhanced operational efficiency and productivity by managing budgets, accounts, and costs.
- Managed day-to-day business operations.
- Consulted with customers to assess needs and propose optimal solutions.

#### 2019-08 -

## **Property Manager**

Current

- Creating and validating legal lease agreements for tenants
- Negotiating lease rates and terms with tenants
- Understanding Tennessee eviction procedures and enforcing when necessary
- Collecting rent and maintaining a professional relationship with client and tenants.

#### 2020-06 -2023-02

## **Project Manager**

Henegar Homes, LLC

- Developed and initiated projects, managed costs, and monitored performance.
- Identified plans and resources required to meet project goals and objectives.
- Reported status of the projects back to the development team daily
- Achieved project deadlines by coordinating with

- contractors to manage performance.
- Coordinated with cross-functional teams to resolve project issues and mitigate risks.

## **Education**

2015-08 - Bachelor of Science: Psychology and Social Sciences

The University of Tennessee At Chattanooga - Chattanooga, TN

• Awarded Outstanding Senior